I think we have also had some,
I would call them,
from this part of the world.
We've had the public,
throughout of the Chinese presidents,
and in the last, what, 30 minutes, an
hour or so, uh, we also understand
that the Chinese have been
speaking with, uh, uh,
the Russian foreign minister in
Beijing. What do we know about that?
Yeah,
obviously there's been a number of
Jinping has been hosting in Beijing,
the most recent one, uh, this morning,
according to state media,
a meeting with the foreign minister of
Sergey Lavrov. Uh,
w- Wang Yi, the foreign minister of China,
uh, met him yesterday as he's visiting
the capital and essentially reaffirming
and strengthening,
advancing their strategic partnership amid
these, uh,
global economic and trade shocks,
no doubt.
Uh,
so we'll likely get more details out of
of Mr. Lavrov meeting with Xi Jinping, uh,
in the Great Hall of the People in
central Beijing.
But there's been a number of other
Xi Jinping, uh, as well this week. Uh,
the new, uh,
newly appointed president, it
was the party chief of Vietnam, To Lam,
will be meeting with Xi Jinping to
strengthen their, uh, relationship after
what's been decades of spotty, uh,
relationships if not border
skirmishes. But again,
the geopolitical climate right now perhaps
pushing Vietnam and Beijing closer
together as To Lam has
consolidated power in Vietnam as, uh,
the party chief
and now, uh, the president.
We also have the Crown Prince of Abu
Dhabi, uh, Sheikh Khaled bin Mohammed,
visiting Beijing,
as well as Pedro Sanchez, uh,
the Prime Minister
of, uh, Spain.
So you can see the red carpet
out as Beijing tries to paint itself as
the responsible
party, uh, globally, uh,
to other countries
around the w-
world amid what has been a very turbulent
year on the trade front with Trump's
policies of tariffs, as well
as now obviously the Israeli-US war in
Iran.
Uh, this is what, uh,
Xi Jinping had to say about,
uh, you know, sort of a not,
not so veiled, uh,
attack on the United States' policy.
This is what he had to say in a meeting
with Pedro Sanchez, the Prime Minister of
Spain.
[camera shutters] [speaking Chinese]
"The world is beset by turmoil,
and the international order is in
disarray.
How a country treats the international law
reflects its world view, its values,
its vision of order,
and its sense of responsibility."
Now, Spain has been one of the more, uh,
outspoken critics of the
war of European nations. This
is Sanchez's fourth meeting
with Xi Jinping in the last three years.
So, uh, despite, you know, uh, Beijing
potentially and essentially losing an ally
in, with the
ouster of, uh, Viktor Orban in Hungary,
uh, Spain
is perhaps picking up a little bit of a
bigger role in, uh, having
closer dialogue with Beijing.